<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Omicron Citizen Series</title><description>Ruminations on music, coding and growing pains.</description><link>http://localhost:2368/</link><image><url>http://localhost:2368/favicon.png</url><title>Omicron Citizen Series</title><link>http://localhost:2368/</link></image><generator>Ghost 1.0</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 05:11:43 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:2368/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>I Listened to More Life</title><description>A Vainglorious Media outlet. So I finally listened to More Life. No, *really* listened. Played it straight through from 1 to 22. No skipping...</description><link>http://localhost:2368/2017/06/05/i-listened-to-more-life/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">59324ee54cfa7177181988af</guid><category>drake</category><category>more life</category><category>about me</category><category>personal</category><category>more life album review</category><category>drake album review</category><dc:creator>Vainglorious</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 05:58:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2017/06/piotr-chrobot-276746.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2017/06/piotr-chrobot-276746.jpg" alt="I Listened to More Life"&gt;&lt;p&gt;So I finally listened to More Life. No, &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; listened. Played it straight through from 1 to 22. No skipping around the album or around the tracks. I also tried to contain other activity to a minimum so I could really focus on the music.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I didn't like it. 2/5 at the absolute max. I mean I love Drake. My wife calls Drake my Patron Saint. It's that serious. But I don't feel the same here. It doesn't give me that So Far Gone, Thank Me Later vibe. Don't get me wrong. He's still himself. He's gonna give you the lines that make you say "damn that ni**a cold" and he's gonna give you the tracks that bump or make you reminisce. That's just his steez. And I know that it's labeled as a "playlist" but More Life was an utter disappointment for fans like me who were hoping for more of a Take Care 2.0 versus Views or IYRTITL 2.0 (that's "If You're Reading This It's Too Late," for the uninitiated). And that's fine I guess. Drake gets paid regardless. I was just hoping for more Drake from More Life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.giphy.com/media/UZ41SqwgD7AtO/giphy.gif" alt="I Listened to More Life"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When that one bar hits you right in the feels&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I know that people say there are a lot of Jamaicans and West Indians in Toronto but that doesn't make Drake Jamaican. The same way a white person with a lot of black friends can't be black. Ever. The culture vulture shit is wack to me. It would be different if... Well, if a lot of things. If the music was good, if he did the accent well, if he had a song or two (instead of half an album) paying homage and acknowledging the Jamaican artists that inspire him but it just comes off gimmicky. The fact that there were Jamaican and British artists on the album doesn't go unnoticed by me. But rapping about your Jamaican friends in a poor accent and letting them and your British buds hop on the track ain't the same as paying homage. At all.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I don't want to hear a dancehall beat every other song. I get that he's an artist but straight ripping other people's culture for personal/commercial gain does not constitute art as far as I'm concerned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, I love Drake. I love the punchlines and the mixture of sadboi kinda-singing R&amp;amp;B (who hurt you?); slow-going introspective lines and hard witty bars that body ni**as. But I didn't really get that on More Life. I want to hear from that Drake on the next release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People don't understand my attachment to "that" Drake. But we close in age. I feel like I grew up with that ni**a lowkey. I was newly 19 when So Far Gone came out and there was nothing else like it in mainstream consciousness to the best of my recollection. Dudes were calling him p***y and just going on my man literally for being human and expressing his humanity on wax. But I fucked with it so heavy. He was a regular dude with both feelings of insecurity and feelings of being the shit; failure and triumphs and plain old tries. And he had bars about it. I used to listen to Houstatlantavegas when I was first learning to drive and I would go see my then girlfriend (now wife) on late nights. The straight up vibes on that joint helped me remain calm, even when I was sure I had no idea where I was going. I went the wrong way down a highway ramp one time and had to promptly turn my ass back around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2017/06/new-driver.png" alt="I Listened to More Life"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I apologize to everybody that shared the road with me back then&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That same year, I started my first "real job" selling TVs and computers (mostly laptops) as well as accessories and addons for TVs and computers for a big box store. Some wild stuff happened at my mom's that turned the household upside down and I moved in with my girl and took my half brother and half sister (we share a father and they share both parents) with me. In 2010, when Thank Me Later dropped, I was regularly commuting between work and my new home and it was heat. I have never forgotten the way I felt listening to it the first couple times on my way home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My dad died early 2011. I got super depressed and stopped going to the job that I hated by that time. They terminated me. That's ok. I'll get another, I told myself. My lady and I started looking for somewhere else to stay because it was pretty cramped in that one bedroom apartment with 2 extra bodies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.giphy.com/media/7S6K3cc58aTzq/giphy.gif" alt="I Listened to More Life"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I got that message...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the time Take Care was coming out, we were getting ready to close on a house and... I was a straight up stan. Other people had come around, too. When Marvin's Room came out it was a wrap. Then Headlines and Make Me Proud. Smash after smash after smash. Drake had 2011-2012 locked down harder than a prison riot. He exploded that year. And I was ecstatic about all the fire music he put out. I played Headlines to the point that I still know the words after not hearing it for at least 2 years and even so, I probably couldn't stand to listen to it at this point because I'm just that fatigued.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Late 2012, I got a call from a gentleman asking me if I was still on the market and still interested in a job that I applied to months earlier. I wanted to say, "hell yeah!" because I hadn't worked since my dad died, despite applying like crazy on a daily basis but I said "yes, sir, when can I start?" I had to pass a moderately difficult interview and get the usual work-up; drug test, background check and fingerprints. I would officially be on the rolls January 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.giphy.com/media/12zd7J5yCcV476/giphy.gif" alt="I Listened to More Life"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When can I start? Yesterday? Lemme get in my DeLorean. Brb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing Was The Same came out in September but my new schedule kept me from getting a chance to listen to it. The job ended up sending me to some paid training out of state; my first flight in a long time.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I loaded up NWTS on my iPhone 4, made sure I packed my headphones and went on my way. I got settled in my exit row window seat, put my headphones in and just listened from start to finish. Twice, I think. Then I just sat with it. It was a total departure from Take Care, but it grew on me. The samples, the overall production of it. How some songs blended into each other. It was great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IYRTITL came out as I was becoming intensely disillusioned with my job at the time. But I had my work ni**as and I made the best of it that I could. I would give my homies rides home bumping Legend, Preach, Energy and on and on. I know they got tired of it. It was even more of a departure in some ways but it still was kind of a banger in other ways so I let it rock, accepting it for what it was. What a Time To Be Alive came out the following September and I think I had all but given up on "old" Drake. I was still interested to see what he put out and hype about the release. WATTBA didn't disappoint. The energy was high and the tracks hit hard. From production to delivery it seemed like a win to me, as far as the new style goes. 30 for 30 felt like "home" but it definitely didn't match the energy of the rest of the project. Gave me hope though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2016 brought Views and happily trounced that hope, with too many forgettable tracks, lyrics that too often either fell flat or felt empty, too much dancehall for a non-Jamaican artist and a lot of 80s and early 90s production influences that appear random as far as selection and placement, so the record as a whole comes off as lacking in cohesion, direction and fire. The dancehall joints bump, of course, but that's because dancehall is dance music. I don't much attribute it to having made good music on Drake's part. A couple stand outs to me were 9, Redemption stuck with me, Weston Road Flows, Still Here and Fire &amp;amp; Desire. I know that sounds like a lot but 5 songs off a 20 song project? Eh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.giphy.com/media/xTiTnkFneD1je4rPOM/giphy.gif" alt="I Listened to More Life"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How I feel about "Views"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which brings us back to More Life. Y'all already know how I feel about that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here's the thing. I didn't completely hate it. It's just not the greatness I was expecting. A couple things that stood out were on Jorja Interlude where he reused (or maybe resampled) Stevie Wonder's sax solo. 4422 is smooth thanks to Sampha. Gyalchester a legit bop. Like uncontested summer jam type shit. Portland is a popular single but I ain't feeling it. I listen to it because it's familiar from the radio playing it back to back but when I sit with it, it's not a song I pick out to listen to for personal enjoyment. It's background music. Teenage Fever straight; the sample and the heavy-lidded pace make it easy listening. Lose You aight, Can't Have Everything started out well but the syncopated flow was a little &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; off. Glow was straight. Since Way Back was aight even though it's kinda long; that's to be expected with the song taking it pretty slow. Ice Melts had some weird parts lyrically and in the ad libs but it was straight. DND is your typical "Drake's journal" type track. I can dig it. Needless to say, the second half of the album was way better than the first half for me. Considering it's 22 tracks long and nearly an hour and a half lengthwise, that's one hell of a build up. And the payoff is meager if I'm completely honest. Still, it's a decent album by today's standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I went on a tangent there. This isn't a Drake or More Life review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My point is... I feel like we've grown apart. On the one hand, I get it. Once you get to be so big a personality, you gotta "turn it on" regardless and give the people what they want so you can make your money. On the other hand, I think some people still want (and will pay for) good music and expect better. I know I do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ja-fakin' shit corny regardless. But here's to Drake. The good, bad and ugly. To my own surprise, I'm quite curious what the next project will sound like. I got my fingers crossed for a dancehall-free release. And here's to me. I set out on a journey to be an adult almost 10 years ago, having no idea where it would lead or what was entailed. I've been through it all. And, even though all signs point to more of the same--as with Drake--I'm still intrigued and excited to see what lies ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>If She's Naggin', You're Laggin'</title><description>A Vainglorious Media outlet. The first relationship post.</description><link>http://localhost:2368/2017/03/30/if-shes-naggin-youre-laggin/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">59324c564cfa7177181988ae</guid><category>grinding</category><category>doing good</category><category>love and family</category><category>work-life balance</category><dc:creator>Vainglorious</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 05:43:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2017/06/jakub-skafiriak-567-1.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2017/06/jakub-skafiriak-567-1.jpg" alt="If She's Naggin', You're Laggin'"&gt;&lt;p&gt;My first relationship post. I know a lot of y'all reading are probably too young to have wives but I am certain you​ have other women in your life and this applies to them as well.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Women (and feminine people) are socialized to give. Women are the first responders emotionally, the aid-givers mentally and physically. They lift everyone up as best they can and when a load is too heavy for someone they love, they shoulder it. In return, I feel they ask for very little and it would benefit everybody in the situation if we all tried to rise to the occasion instead of asking her to accept less so you can grind. I admit to being at fault here, too. I struggle with finding a that happy medium between working and not working (quality time with family, self-care, etc). But I try to curb my obsessiveness and be good to the people around me by keeping a few things in mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't act like she's a nag or a bother. Before you get all defensive, I'm not belittling the grind. The grind is essential to creating a successful business. What I'm saying is that you can be more aware of and accountable for the things you're supposed to do for your "right now" life, too. The things that can and should be done while you grind. If the woman in your life has reminded you to take out the trash (or handle whatever other tasks you're supposed to) 5 times and you're still deep-diving in your DAW, you're lagging. And that's just what's real. For one thing, that's your duty. She's not asking you to climb Mount Everest. She's trying to get you to do something you should've already done. For two, you might use 10 minutes taking out the trash but the positive effects go far beyond the time it requires. Simple acts where you're taking care of business reinforce that you're an active participant in your relationship with that woman. It serves to remind her that she's important to you and help her feel valued and validated in continuing to support you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea that long term gain beats short term pain takes over quick, though. And the reason the grind can, in your mind, take precedence over everything because it's so easy to think "when I'm on, things will be better" and daydream about how you'll be able to take care of everybody you love. And that is a noble pursuit, but you can't ignore the other parts of your life in favor of grinding alone. The things you drop so you can grind have to be done by someone. And there's probably a woman in your life taking up that slack so you can do your thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2017/06/dragon_slayer_by_vicki73-d5r1s00.jpg" alt="If She's Naggin', You're Laggin'"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slay dragons!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not saying don't reach for your goals. Nah. Grind hard! Believe in yourself! Conquer your demons and slay your dragons! But sometimes a dose of reality is helpful in remaining grounded and prioritizing for the position you're in currently. Nothing is guaranteed. You may not "make it" as a producer. You may never be wealthy. That's the truth. But the people that have loved you and cared for you will need you regardless and you need them, too. Not only in the future or the past but in the present as well. You need them right now. You can't let those connections die on the vine for the sake of grinding. Nourish your close relationships and cherish those people. Especially the women in your life. She (whoever "she" may be; wife, mother, girlfriend, best friend) is never going to tell your how weighed down and anxious and depressed she is. She's going to put on a brave face for you, laugh at your stupid jokes and love you. She's going to provide the light you use to see the end of the tunnel. Live up to it. Be the kind of guy that can say, "I deserve this." From your wives, your mothers, your daughters, your aunts. Be worthy of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or at least do your best not to have her riding your back about something she already told you to do multiple times. I promise she hates it just as much as you do. (Probably more.) Trust me. I'm married. I know these things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2017/06/pablo--1-.png" alt="If She's Naggin', You're Laggin'"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Grind&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point of contention is striking that balance where you feel like you're going at a pace that will allow you to meet your goals while being there for your family and friends. I don't have all the answers, Sway. But I know for sure that it's worth it to try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S.: This post is not meant to leave out the men and masculine people. Not at all. If the men in your life are doing the emotional work of supporting you, acknowledge that. But in general, your homeboys, uncles, dads and granddads won't be carrying the same emotional burden as the women. They're not the ones you call when you're about to break down because you feel like it's never going to happen for you. You call mom dukes. You call grandma. You call aunty or bestie. You cry (or don't). You share the heft of your feelings and insecurities about the situation. And they help you carry it. They encourage you. Hell, sometimes they carry you through it, if I'm completely honest. So what I'm saying is: honor them. Honor their contributions to your life and make them feel all the things they make you feel: loved, significant, supported, believed in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go. Do it naooo. (&lt;em&gt;Arnold voice&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attributions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vicki73 for the Skyrim "dragon slayer" photo manipulation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I forgot where I got the "Manhattanhenge" photo. But if it's yours or you know the photographer, please let me know. Happy to give them credit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Back for the First Time</title><description>A Vainglorious Media outlet. Starting out it can be hard to know which tools you need and which make your life easier...</description><link>http://localhost:2368/2017/03/21/back-for-the-first-time/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5932498a4cfa7177181988a6</guid><category>getting started</category><category>new producers</category><category>producing</category><category>hardware and gear</category><dc:creator>Vainglorious</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 05:30:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2017/06/wesley-caribe-63610.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2017/06/wesley-caribe-63610.jpg" alt="Back for the First Time"&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you begin studying a new craft that you want to practice, it can be hard to distinguish between the tools you need to get the job done and "convenience" tools that are used make your life easier. It's something I definitely struggled with as a new producer so I want to put this out there for producers that will be new after me.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I have no doubt you have heard the quote, "The journey of a thousand miles begins with a single step." I actually may have paraphrased a little but my point is, you have to start. You can't start the journey if you want to finish another mixing article, top 10 [insert item] list or watch one more tutorial on something you haven't even tried yet. You also can't start if you're trying to save up for that new piece of gear with the amazing tech that you've been following the development of for months now.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
And even seasoned craftspeople that don't have everything they'd like to have sometimes need reminders, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tell me if you've seen this before on Snapchat, Instagram, YouTube or wherever you do your social media thing:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Studio monitors - $700&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Video monitor(s) - $200+&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
MIDI Keyboard - $150&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Monitor stands - $75&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Audio Interface - $300&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Desk - $100&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generalization: Pros use outboard gear and other hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many pros have (or use at their studio) hardware compressors and reverbs, large format consoles and all manner of cool looking gadget; none of which is needed to start. And the keyword there is start. Based on my research and personal experience, the reasons for outboard gear can be condensed to really 4 main things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;familiarity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;workflow enhancement/save time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pleasure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;specialty (getting that "certain sound" or "x factor")&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of that is necessary to begin. Literally. All you truly need is the software (DAW) and a way to hear what you're making. Now you might be thinking how to pick a DAW or which DAW is best. Before you Google that, let me save you some time here: there is no perfect DAW. There's no best DAW. There's no DAW with "the best" sound. There's only the right tool at the right time. What's perfect for you now may not be a fit down the line or may not work for you for a given task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally I use Ableton. I love it and I do everything in it, but I've had to realize that it does have its shortcomings. While it's great for sketching and composition there are DAWs that do a better job with vocal comping and mixing, for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what's the answer then? What do you need to start? You need patience, resolve and creativity. Decide what you're creating and pick a DAW. Then pick another if you need to; I'm not judging. Find your fit. Discover how you like to work and find the program that offers you the least resistance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think about it two ways: you have more time than you have money or you have more money than you have time. If you have more time than money then you should take the time to learn your DAW because it can do nearly anything that can be accomplished with hardware. If you have more money than time then get one or two things that will improve your workflow or efficiency. This might come in the form of improved sound via studio monitors or improved ergonomics in your studio or pretty much anything you can think of that will increase productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either way, the gear doesn't make the music. You do. Tools are just tools at the end of the day. They're instruments for doing your work. Don't get lost in response curves and specs on rack mount reverbs and other wild internet rabbit holes. Whatever you pick, however you decide to configure things, the sounds that come out of it all come down to you creating and shaping them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make the music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>One Hurdle at a Time</title><description>A Vainglorious Media outlet. This past week, I've been pondering the usefulness of YouTube because it's incredibly difficult to break through...</description><link>http://localhost:2368/2017/03/14/one-hurdle-at-a-time/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5932473a4cfa717718198893</guid><category>video editing</category><category>problem solving</category><category>troubleshooting</category><category>adobe</category><category>premiere pro</category><category>after effects</category><category>beatmaking</category><category>youtube</category><category>networking</category><dc:creator>Vainglorious</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 05:21:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2017/06/leandro-puca-184754.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2017/06/leandro-puca-184754.jpg" alt="One Hurdle at a Time"&gt;&lt;p&gt;This past week, I've been pondering the usefulness of YouTube because it's incredibly difficult to break through to a wide audience at this point but I did find myself using it to be seen on other people's videos and kind of start building out a network with other producers. With that in mind, I figure once I've done enough networking, people will start coming to my channel and it might be a bit weird for them to find it empty. So yesterday finds me making my first beat video for YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And... to summarize, painful is the only word I can think of. Seriously. I opened the video editor, having only used it briefly for looping or chopping shorter videos together. My first thought is, "well, what do I start with?" I didn't have stock footage. I didn't have anything original so I picked an action-packed episode of this anime. Why anime? Well, I'm a nerd and I love anime and I was hoping to create something that would hold people's attention. My beats are experimental; give me a break. Turns out I really have no idea what I'm doing. I'm looking up shortcuts and how to's for simple stuff every few minutes because I am just lost. Not to mention the mini meltdowns from frustration and sleepiness. Don't even get me started on scrubbing 30 minutes of video for good stuff to use; sometimes there wasn't enough and at other times, I had to make some tough decisions on what would stay. I didn't want to use sequences that were too long lest I call forth the mighty Copyright Strike Hammer of YouTube upon myself. Nobody wants that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did I mention that it's probably already past midnight at that point in my struggle? The night before I was up until at least 3:30am drinking with my family. My nephew had his second birthday party but it was a Saturday so after the kids went down, the adults elected to have some fun, too. So I'm drinking and drinking. By the time I'm ready to go, I'm toasted. But the night is over. I can lay in my bed and get some shut-eye. Sweet. This was a good day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost. I wake up 9 hours later extremely dehydrated but I say to myself you know I can drink some water, take some Advil and power through it. I've been trying to flesh out this video idea for a week so now it's time for some execution. Needless to say, I am lagging. I barely get anything done. Finally, I go down for a nap and I sleep until like 10:45 that night; maybe later. I get up like holy crap what time is it? The video. I haven't done anything really. So back to working on the video; past midnight already.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I'm getting toward the end and I start to feel accomplished until I remember I haven't even touched the FX program and my video was too short when I added the audio playback. So I'm going in trying to quickly add time without messing up my sequence. Okay, 6 seconds left to fill. I can see the light at the end of the tunnel! And I make it but then I remember I didn't leave room for an intro. /headdesk/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Had to look up encoder settings for YouTube and watch a few videos. Tim was extremely helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Encoding. It's 4am now. I have to be up and at 'em at 9 so I can make an appointment at 10. Probably pushing that back. And just when I think I can relax because I've gotten something done, I remember all the other stuff that goes into a song release. I've gotta write a description and decide on some tags, but not too many but with terms that aren't too broad either. I got a thumbnail to adjust (shoutout Foreign for the template).&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I have to say, it was an ordeal. But I'm glad I got through it and I do have my video to show for it plus the experience for future videos. I'll be that much faster next time. But alas, old habits as they say. It's 6:31am (the following day; or is it 2 days later now? I might be delirious) and I haven't been to bed yet. What is my life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, you've suffered enough. Here's the video. Don't judge me. I'm terrible at "typing" my beats but I'm working on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/k8-iGtw1Vb4" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's so much that goes into being a one man operation. If there are any beatmakers (or video makers) reading this, please share. How did your first video go? If you have any questions or tips, definitely let me know!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until next time. Don't be a stranger though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>